A Finding Aid to the George Leslie Stout papers, 1855, 1897-1978, in the Archives of American Art AAA.stougeor
Archives of American Art
George Leslie Stout papers
1897-1978
1855
AAA.stougeor
Archives of American Art
5.8 Linear feet
The papers of conservator and museum director George Leslie Stout measure 5.8 linear feet and date from 1855, 1897-1978. Stout was head of the conservation department at Harvard University's Fogg Art Museum, director of the Worcester Art Museum and Isabella Stewart Gardner Museum in Massachusetts, and a member of the Monuments, Fine Art and Archives (MFAA) Section of the U.S. Army during World War II. The bulk of the collection consists of correspondence with family, friends, colleagues and professional associations. There are letters from fellow Monuments Men who served in the MFAA section such as Thomas Carr Howe, Ardelia Hall, Lamont Moore, Theodore Sizer, Langdon Warner and several other prominent arts administrators. The papers also contain biographical materials, writings, sketches and one sketchbook, military records, printed materials, and photographs.
Stout, George L. (George Leslie)
Biographical/Historical note
George Leslie Stout (1897-1978) was a museum director and prominent art conservator in Massachusetts. Stout was head of the conservation department at Harvard University's Fogg Art Museum, and director of the Worcester Art Museum and Isabella Stewart Gardner Museum, Massachusetts. During World War II, Stout served in the U.S. Army Monuments, Fine Art and Archives (MFAA) and played a leading role in the protection, location, and recovery of art work stolen by the Nazis.
Born in Winterset, Iowa in 1897, George Leslie Stout was the oldest of six children and attended Winterset High School and served in the U.S. army during World War I. Following the war, Stout studied at the State University of Iowa, received his B.A. in 1921, worked for a few years, and married Margaret Hayes in 1924 with whom he had two sons, Robert and Thomas. He attended Harvard graduate school in 1926 and graduated with a Master of Art in 1929. Stout began working as a lecturer and conservator at Harvard's Fogg Art Museum, later becoming the head of the conservation department in 1933, a position he held until 1947.
During World War II, Stout re-enlisted in the U.S. Navy, having served in the reserves since World War I. Stout was one of the first members of the Monuments, Fine Arts & Archives (MFAA) Section of the U.S. army. He was appointed to the MFAA Section for the Twelfth Army Group in 1944 and was one of the first Monuments Men to arrive at Normandy, France. He was later appointed Lieutenant Commander of the MFAA Section. Many of the Monuments Men's stolen art recovery achievements were directed by George Leslie Stout. Stout supervised the inventory and removal of looted art hidden by the Nazis in the salt mines of Merkers and Ransbach in Thuringia, Germany. Stout oversaw the organization, packing, and shipping of several thousand objects including paintings by Rubens and Goya, along with precious antiquities. At the Altaussee salt mines in Austria, he was in charge of the unit that recovered a large cache of stolen artwork that included Michelangelo's Madonna and Child and the Ghent Altarpiece or The Adoration of the Mystic Lamb by Hubert and Jan van Eyck. There, he also worked very closely with fellow Monuments Men Thomas Carr Howe. Stout went on to locate and recover looted artwork in other repositories in Germany, France, and the Netherlands. He maintained a relationship with many of his fellow Monuments Men after the war.
Stout left Europe in the latter half of 1945, then went to Japan where he served as the Chief of the Arts and Monuments Division at Headquarters of the Supreme Commander for the Allied Powers, Tokyo until the middle of 1946. After the war Stout received the Bronze Star and the Army Commendation Medal for his army service and work as a Monuments Man in Europe.
Stout resumed his position as the head of the conservation department at the Fogg Art Museum when he returned to America. In 1947 he became the director of the Worcester Art Museum in Massachusetts where he stayed until 1955, when he became the director of the Isabella Stewart Gardner Museum in Boston where he worked until his retirement in 1970. Stout wrote numerous articles about art conservation and wrote two books: Painting Materials, A Short Encyclopaedia (1942), co-authored with Harvard colleage R. J. Gettens, and Care of Pictures (1948). Stout died in Menlo Park, California in 1978 and was widely recognized as a distinguished art conservator.
Arrangement note
This collection is arranged as 9 series.
Series 1: Biographical Materials, circa 1919-1977 (0.1 linear feet; Box 1)
Series 2: Correspondence, 1922-1978 (2.5 linear feet; Box 1-3, OV 8)
Series 3: Writings, 1927-1978 (0.5 linear feet; Box 3-4)
Series 4: Subject Files, 1918, 1943-1978 (1 linear feet; Box 4, OV 8-9)
Series 5: Monuments, Fine Arts & Archives Section Files, 1918, 1942-1955, 1972-1975 (0.5 linear feet; Box 5)
Series 6: Personal Business Records, 1938-1978 (0.1 linear feet; Box 5)
Series 7: Printed Materials, 1926-1977 (0.8 linear feet; Box 5-6, OV 9)
Series 8: Sketchbooks, circa 1924-circa 1938, 1970-1977 (0.1 linear feet; Box 6)
Series 9: Photographic Materials, circa 1855, 1897-1978 (0.2 linear feet; Box 6-7)
Conditions Governing Access note
The George Leslie Stout papers are owned by the Archives of American Art, Smithsonian Institution. Literary rights as possessed by the donor have been dedicated to public use for research, study, and scholarship. The collection is subject to all copyright laws.
Existence and Location of Copies note
Portions of this collection are available on 35 mm microfilm reels 1378, 1420-1425, and 1427 at Archives of American Art offices, and through interlibrary loan. Researchers should note that the microfilmed order does not reflect the current arrangement of the papers.
Immediate Source of Acquisition note
George Leslie Stout donated his papers to the Archives of American Art in 1978.
Related Archival Materials note
Also found in the Archives of American Art is an oral history interview with George Stout conducted by Paul Karlstrom in 1978.
Separated Materials note
In 1978, Robert Stout, son of George Stout, loaned four diaries to the Archives of American Art for microfilming on Reel 1378. The diaries were returned to Robert Stout, son of George Stout, after microfilming. Stout describes his experiences surveying war-caused damages in France, Germany, and Japan, and the recovery of Nazi impounded art works. Several letters, memos, personal documents, printed matter, and a photograph of U.S. military personnel and others viewing an art exhibit, are included in the diaries. The diaries are not described in the container list of this finding aid.
Scope and Contents note
The papers of conservator and museum director George Leslie Stout measure 5.8 linear feet and date from 1855, 1897-1978. Stout was head of the conservation department at Harvard University's Fogg Art Museum, director of the Worcester Art Museum and Isabella Stewart Gardner Museum in Massachusetts, and a member of the Monuments, Fine Art and Archives (MFAA) Section of the U.S. Army during World War II. The bulk of the collection consists of correspondence with family, friends, colleagues and professional associations. There are letters from fellow Monuments Men who served in the MFAA section such as Thomas Carr Howe, Ardelia Hall, Lamont Moore, Theodore Sizer, Langdon Warner and several other prominent arts administrators. The papers also contain biographical materials, writings, sketches and one sketchbook, military records, printed materials, and photographs.
Biographical materials include college and graduate school transcripts, various certificates, four small appointment books and passports.
Correspondence is between George Leslie Stout and family, friends, colleagues, professional associations and fellow Monuments Men. Family correspondence is with Stout's immediate and extended family, the bulk of which is from Stout to his wife Margaret and his son Thomas. Correspondents in the Monuments Men correspondence include Thomas Carr Howe, Ardelia Hall, Lamont Moore, Theodore Sizer, Langdon Warner, and many others. There is also substantial correspondence with friends and professional colleagues in the museum and art world, such as Walter Beck, Richard D. Buck, William George Constable, Earl of Crawford, George Peabody Gardner, Jr., William Ivins, Jr., Henri Marceau, and Paul Sachs, among many others.
Writings by Stout consist of typescript drafts and published articles, speeches, and miscellaneous notes. Most of the writings concern art conservation and the speeches are memorials for two of Stout's colleagues. Notes consists of drafts for the texts of holiday cards Stout designed, biographical notes, and images and captions for The Care of Pictures. There are also three conference papers on art conservation written by other people.
Subject files document Stout's conservation projects as a consultant for museums, universities, galleries and other organizations. Also found in this series are documents relating to Stout's work after retiring from the Isabella Gardner Museum and his membership or participation in various arts programs and organizations.
A separate series contains files relating to Stout's World War II service in the Monuments, Fine Arts & Archives (MFAA) Section. Found here are official military records, publications by Monuments Men, and a few scattered photographs. Military records include directives, reports, certificates and a bronze star medal. There are articles and books written by various Monuments Men such as Langdon Warner, Lincoln Kirstein and Theodore Sizer. There are also scattered photographs, only two of which depict tout (including one group photograph with Lamont Moore, Walker Hancock and other Monuments Men.) There are also 12 negatives with 4 prints depicting La Gleize Church and the town of Ambleve, Belgium in 1945.
Personal business records include assorted legal and estate papers as well as financial papers such as receipts, travel expenses and donations.
Printed materials consists of news clippings, bulletins, brochures, press releases, conference papers, and magazine and journal articles, most of it related to art conservation.
Artwork includes pencil and ink drawings and sketches, mostly of travel scenes, people, and animals. There is one sketchbook of the human figure. Many sketches were loosely grouped together by Stout with titles such as "Pool Doodles" or "Park and Zoo." The is also one caricature of Eric Brown by Murray Pease.
The papers include photographs and negatives, mostly personal photographs of friends, family, relatives and colleagues. There are also photographs of art conservation conferences and travel photographs. Additional scattered photographs are located in the series containing the Monuments Men files.
Allied Forces. Supreme Headquarters. Monuments, Fine Arts and Archives Section.; Buck, Richard D.; Constable, W. G., (William George), 1887-1976; Fogg Art Museum; Gardner, G. Peabody, (George Peabody); Hall, Ardelia Ripley; Howe, Thomas Carr, 1904-1994; Isabella Stewart Gardner Museum.; Ivins, William Mills, Jr., 1881-1961; Marceau, Henri, 1896-1969; Moore, Lamont; Sachs, Paul J. (Paul Joseph), 1878-1965; Sizer, Theodore, 1892-1967; Warner, Langdon, 1881-1955; Worcester Art Museum; Art--Conservation and restoration; Arts administrators; Conservators--California; Museum directors--United States; Photographs; Sketchbooks; Sketches; World War, 1939-1945 -- Art and the war
- Biographical Materials, circa 1919-1977; Series 1; 0.1 Linear feet Box 1
  Scope and Contents note
  Biographical materials include college and graduate school transcripts, awards and commendations, certificates, passports, and miscellaneous materials such as travel itineraries. There are also four small appointment books dating from 1973 and 1975-1977.
  - Sigma Delta Chi Fraternity Certificate, circa 1919 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - University of Iowa Transcript, 1921 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Harvard University Transcript, 1942 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Curriculum Vitae, 1947 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Clark University Honorary Degree, 1955 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - International Institute for Conservation Honorary Fellowship, 1966 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Marquis Who's Who Publications Certification, 1966-1967 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Hill-Stead Museum Letter of Appreciation, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Poem in Honor of Tavern Club Medal, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Record of Stout Family Reunion, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Appointment Books, 1973; 1975 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Appointment Books, 1976-1977 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Margaret Hayes Stout Passports, 1930-1938; 1964 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - George Leslie Stout Passports, 1924-1928 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - George Leslie Stout Passports, 1933-1964 (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Correspondence, 1922-1978; Series 2; 2.5 Linear feet Box 1-3, OV 8
  Correspondence is with family, friends, colleagues, fellow Monuments Men, and professional organizations such as museums and universities.
  Arrangement note
  This series is arranged as 5 subseries:
  2.1: Family, 1925-1978
  2.2: Monuments Men, 1930-1978
  2.3: Friends and Colleagues, 1922-1978
  2.4: Professional, 1925-1978
  2.5: Miscellaneous, 1923-1978
  - Family, 1925-1978; 2.1
    Family correspondence is primarily between George Leslie Stout and his immediate and extended family, most of it with his wife Margaret during his World War II service.
    - Hayes, Helen, circa 1945 (Box 1, Folder 16)
      Helen Hayes is George Leslie Stout's sister-in-law.
    - Stout, Abe, 1925; 1972-1978; 1942 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Stout, Betty, 1973-1977 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Stout, Carolyn W., 1976 (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - Stout, Charles H. ("Chick"), 1941; 1974-1976 (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - Stout, John, 1971-1977 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - Stout, LuLu McBride, circa 1926; 1941 (Box 1, Folder 22)
      LuLu McBride Stout is George Stout's mother.
    - Stout, Margaret, 1943-1944 (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - Stout, Margaret, 1944-1945 (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - Stout, Margaret, 1945-1946 (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - Stout, Margaret, 1946-1977 (Box 1, Folder 26)
    - Stout, Robert, 1945 (Box 1, Folder 27)
    - Stout, Sarah M., 1977 (Box 1, Folder 28)
    - Stout, Stephen P. ("Tubby"), 1972-1978 (Box 1, Folder 29)
    - Stout, "Stibbits", 1918 (Box 1, Folder 30)
    - Stout, Thomas, circa 1944-1951 (Box 1, Folder 31)
    - Stout, Thomas, 1972-1977; 1952-1954 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Monuments Men, bulk 1943-1950; 1930-1978; 2.2
    This subseries consists of letters exchanged between Stout and other Monuments Men such as Paul Coremans, Ardelia Hall, Thomas Carr Howe, Lincoln Kirstein, Stephen Kovalyk, Lamont Moore, Theodore Sizer, Craig Hugh Smyth, Langdon Warner, and many others. Several of the Monuments Men went on to prominent careers in the arts and Stout stayed in contact. There is also one letter from Haruki Watsuji, the mayor of Kyoto while Stout was serving as a Monuments Man in Japan after the war. The letter mentions Stout and fellow Monuments Man Langdon Warner visiting Kyoto. There is also a Christmas card signed by members of the U.S. Twelfth Army Group. A few records are in French.
    - Coremans, Paul, 1947-1948; 1974 (Box 1, Folder 33)
    - De Vries, A. B., 1975; 1977 (Box 1, Folder 34)
    - Dixon-Spain, J. E., 1944-1957 (Box 1, Folder 35)
    - Hall, Ardelia, 1947 (Box 1, Folder 36)
    - Hancock, Walker, 1974-1976; 1948 (Box 1, Folder 37)
    - Howe, Thomas Carr, 1945-1977 (Box 1, Folder 38)
      Oversized material housed in OV 8, Folder 1.
      Includes one color photograph of George Stout seated at a dinner with M.F.K. Fisher and two photocopies of caricatures drawn by the artist Thomas Buechner.
    - Kirstein, Lincoln, 1961-1977; 1947 (Box 1, Folder 39)
    - Kovalyk, Stephen, 1974-1976; 1946-1947 (Box 1, Folder 40)
    - Lee, Sherman, 1972; 1946-1947 (Box 1, Folder 41)
    - Moore, Lamont, 1977; 1947 (Box 1, Folder 42)
    - Parkhurst, Charles, 1977-1978 (Box 1, Folder 43)
    - Ross, Marvin C., 1974 (Box 1, Folder 44)
    - Sickman, Laurence, 1946-1947; 1977 (Box 1, Folder 45)
    - Sizer, Theodore, 1954; 1947 (Box 1, Folder 46)
    - Smyth, Craig Hugh, 1976; 1959-1960 (Box 1, Folder 47)
    - Warner, Langdon, circa 1930-1954 (Box 1, Folder 48)
    - Watsuji, Haruki, 1946 (Box 1, Folder 49)
      There is also a black and white group photograph of Stout with Japanese government officials and two Americans, one is probably Langdon Warner and the other is unidentified.
    - Twelfth Army Group Holiday Menu, 1944 (Box 1, Folder 50)
      This is a Twelfth Army Group Holiday Menu Card for Christmas 1944 signed by several army members of various ranks.
    - Oversized Floor Plans, 1970-1972 (Box OV 8, Folder 1)
      Oversized material from Box 1, Folder 38.
  - Friends and Colleagues, 1922-1978; 2.3
    This subseries contains correspondence with Stout's friends and professional colleagues. Prominent, frequent, or otherwise important correspondents include Walter Beck, Richard D. Buck, William George Constable, Earl of Crawford and Balcarres, George Peabody Gardner, Jr., Rutherford John Gettens, Rollin Hadley, Philip Hendy, William Ivins, Jr., Helmut Ruhemann, and Paul Sachs (Harvard professor and author.)
    - Asmus, John F., 1974-1976 (Box 1, Folder 51)
    - Beck, Walter, 1930-1952 (Box 1, Folder 52)
    - Brazier, Mollie, 1976-1977 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Buck, Robin and Richard (Dick), 1971-1978 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Carter, Morris, 1938-1954 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Cary, Otis, circa 1974-1975 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Constable, Olivia and W. G., 1933-1946; circa 1976 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Cox, Yvonne, circa 1976 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Crawford and Balcarres, Earl of, 1970-1971; 1947-1951 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Cross, Harold F., 1973; 1977 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - De Wilde, A. Martin, 1937-1947 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Ehrlich, William and Evelyn, 1967-1974 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Frederick, John T. and Esther, 1922-1925 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Gardner, George Peabody, Jr. ("Peabo") and Rose, 1954-1972 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Gardner, John Lowell, circa 1974 (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Gettens, Rutherford J. and Katherine, 1970-1977; 1958 (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Goetz, William, 1960 (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - Gregg, Richard N., circa 1972-1978 (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - Hadley, Rollin ("Bump"), 1972-1976 (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - Hayes, Marian, 1947; 1970 (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - Hendy, Philip, 1947-1948; 1972-1975 (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - Hodnett, Ted, 1974-1976 (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - Hunt, Percival, circa 1922-1925; circa 1947 (Box 2, Folder 21)
    - Ivins, William, circa 1941-1949 (Box 2, Folder 22)
    - Jacobi, Lotte, 1978; 1975 (Box 2, Folder 23)
    - Jefferson, Howard B., 1974-1977; 1955 (Box 2, Folder 24)
    - Laurie, A. P., circa 1932-1936 (Box 2, Folder 25)
    - Longstreet, Gilbert W., 1972-1978 (Box 2, Folder 26)
    - Mahoney, Dennis, 1975-1977 (Box 2, Folder 27)
    - McGee, John, 1976-1978 (Box 2, Folder 28)
    - Muilenburg, Walter J., 1923 (Box 2, Folder 29)
    - Muller, Norman E., 1973-1977 (Box 2, Folder 30)
    - Newton, Travers, 1974-1975 (Box 2, Folder 31)
    - Nicholson, Virginia and W.E. (Nick), circa 1975 (Box 2, Folder 32)
    - Oikawa-Picante, Teri, 1972-1977 (Box 2, Folder 33)
    - Peabody, Sara and Frank, 1974-1975 (Box 2, Folder 34)
    - Pease, Murray, 1944-1954 (Box 2, Folder 35)
    - Penasco, Eduardo Nunez J., 1953-1954 (Box 2, Folder 36)
    - Petersen, Nancy, 1974-1978 (Box 2, Folder 37)
    - Plenderleith, Harold J., 1940-1976 (Box 2, Folder 38)
    - Pope, Arthur, 1954; 1970-1974 (Box 2, Folder 39)
    - Rawlins, F. Ian G., 1940-1969 (Box 2, Folder 40)
    - Ross, Thorvald S., 1938-1939 (Box 2, Folder 41)
    - Roth, James, 1971-1975 (Box 2, Folder 42)
    - Ruhemann, Helmut, 1932-1953 (Box 2, Folder 43)
      Includes a black and white photograph of Helmut Ruhemann.
    - Sachs, Paul, 1947 (Box 2, Folder 44)
    - Sawyer, Charles H., 1974-1977 (Box 2, Folder 45)
    - Schwartzbaum, Paul M., 1972-1978 (Box 2, Folder 46)
    - Smith, Frank C. Jr., 1947 (Box 2, Folder 47)
    - Souers, Philip, 1938 (Box 2, Folder 48)
    - Stinson, Harry and Ruth, 1972-1975 (Box 2, Folder 49)
    - Swarzenski, Hanns, circa 1973-1977 (Box 2, Folder 50)
    - Thacher, John S., 1971-1976; 1939 (Box 2, Folder 51)
    - Tichane, Robin Myron, 1976-1978 (Box 2, Folder 52)
    - Vance, Philip, 1974-1977 (Box 2, Folder 53)
    - Vigtel, Gudmund, 1977 (Box 2, Folder 54)
    - Ward, Gwen, circa 1977 (Box 2, Folder 55)
    - Webb, Geoffrey, 1946-1947 (Box 2, Folder 56)
    - White, Sherman R., 1972-1974 (Box 2, Folder 57)
  - Professional, 1925-1978; 2.4
    Stout's professional correspondence is with museums, galleries, universities, and other organizations regarding projects or business affairs related to his work as a museum director or art conservation. The Fogg Art Museum folder includes one letter from Agnes Mongan, the museum director, just before her retirement. A few records are in French.
    - American Association of Museums, 1975-1978 (Box 2, Folder 58)
    - American Institute for Conservation of Historic and Artistic Works, 1972-1978 (Box 2, Folder 59)
      The American Institute for Conservation of Historic and Artistic Works was originally called the International Insitute for Conservation of Historic and Artistic Works - American Group. This folder contains letters with both organization titles.
    - Archives of American Art, 1978 (Box 2, Folder 60)
    - Art Association of Montreal, 1947 (Box 2, Folder 61)
    - Art Dealer & Framer, 1977 (Box 2, Folder 62)
    - Asian Art Museum of San Francisco, 1973-1977 (Box 2, Folder 63)
    - Balboa Art Conservation Center, 1976-1978 (Box 2, Folder 64)
    - Bay Area Conservation Study and Guild, 1971-1978 (Box 2, Folder 65)
    - California Department of Parks and Recreation, 1977 (Box 2, Folder 66)
    - Carnegie Corporation, 1925-1926; 1940-1941 (Box 2, Folder 67)
    - Carnegie-Mellon University, 1972-1977 (Box 2, Folder 68)
    - Columbia University Press, 1954-1971 (Box 2, Folder 69)
    - Cooperstown Conservation of Historic and Artistic Works, 1974-1976 (Box 2, Folder 70)
    - D. Van Nostrand Company, Inc., 1942 (Box 2, Folder 71)
    - Dover Publications, 1970-1978 (Box 2, Folder 72)
    - Edmond R. Mansoor Antiquities, 1971-1972 (Box 2, Folder 73)
    - Fogg Art Museum, 1971-1977 (Box 2, Folder 74)
    - Forest Lawn Memorials - Parks and Mortuaries, 1971-1977 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Foundation of the American Institute for Conservation of Historic and Artistic Works, 1976-1977 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Harvard University, 1926-1947 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Innisfree Foundation, 1960-1977 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Institut Royal du Patrimonie Artistique, 1971-1976 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Isabella Stewart Gardner Museum, 1972-1978; 1954-1959 (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - John J. Johnson Collection, 1961-1972 (Box 3, Folder 7)
      Oversized material housed in OV 8, Folder 2.
    - Library of Congress, 1947-1953 (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - Los Angeles County Museum of Art, 1973-1976 (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - The Minneapolis Institute of Arts, 1977-1978; 1958 (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - Museos de Arte de Barcelona, 1954 (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - National Conservation Advisory Council, 1974 (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - The New Yorker, 1947 (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - Oakland Museum, 1977-1978 (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - Portland Art Museum, 1955-1956; 1972-1978 (Box 3, Folder 15)
    - San Francisco Civil Service Commission, 1973 (Box 3, Folder 16)
    - San Simeon, 1970-1976 (Box 3, Folder 17)
    - Smith College Museum of Art, 1954-1955 (Box 3, Folder 18)
    - Stanford University, 1972-1975 (Box 3, Folder 19)